[whooshing sound effects]
[music plays]
Hi, I'm Gidon from Steamy'sCleaning and Restoration Services.
And I'm going to show you how to remove ared wine spill from your carpet.
It is important to do this as soon as theincident happens.
Otherwise, you will need to call aprofessional carpet cleaning company.
Down here, I've got two different type of carpets.
One, is a well treated nylon carpet, theother one is a good quality wool carpet.
Now, I'm going to spill on the nylon oneand that would be on the wool one.
What we need to do is to blot the carpet.
As you can see, the wool one absorbed the wine straight away.
With the nylon, it is sitting on top of the nylon.
What we need to do, we need to blot the stains first.
[soft background music plays]
Now, do not rub the carpet.
If you're going to rub the carpet, you'regoing to create a non-reversible damage to it.
Then, we take salt and we put some salt over the stains.
After waiting for a few minutes, we take a vacuum cleaner and we suck all the salt out.
By this stage, most of the wine should be absorbed by the salt.
Now, if you can still see the stain,
we take a cup of water and we put somebicarbonated soda into it, mix it up,
and then, spread on the stain.
Then, we take a sponge and we try and absorb as much as we can.
Then, we take a cloth again, a clean one and blot again.
As you can see, those two stains are gone now.
[soft music plays]
[Captioning services provided by amara.org]